Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Gracie Mansion Gallery records
1972-1991
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Gracie Mansion Gallery
5.3 linear feet
The records of the New York City contemporary Gracie Mansion Gallery measure 5.3 linear feet and date from 1972-1991. Most of the records date from the gallery opening in 1982 and later. The bulk of the collection consists of printed material and exhibition loan files that document the activities of the gallery and the East Village art scene. Loan and consignment files are found for numerous artists including Michael Bidlo, Buster Cleveland, Claudia DeMonte, Rodney Alan Greenblat, Stephen Lack, Ed McGowin, David Sandlin, Hope Sandrow, David Wojnarowicz, Rhonda Zwillinger, among others. Also found are scattered business records.
Provenance
The Gracie Mansion Gallery records were donated in 1991 by Gracie Mansion, founder of the Gracie Mansion Gallery.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Historical Note
Painter and dealer Joanne Mayhew (b. circa 1947) changed her name to Gracie Mansion in 1982, and opened a gallery in the bathroom of her East Village apartment in March of that same year.
Gracie Mansion's first "Loo Division" exhibition was of her friend's photographs. The previous year, Gracie Mansion helped organize the "Limo Show", for which she rented a limousine and parked it on the corner of Spring and Broadway with fellow artists Buster Cleveland and Sur Rodney Sur. There, dressed as tourists, they served champagne and tried to sell their artwork to passersby.
This grassroots approach to the art market came to typify the emerging East Village art scene. Frustrated by the closed system of the SoHo and 57th Street galleries, in 1981-1982 several young artists and artists' groups began organizing shows and forming makeshift galleries of their own for fun and profit in the more affordable dilapidated East Village. The artwork they sold, predominately paintings, were also more affordable than those in SoHo.
The press quickly picked up on the East Village phenomenon and Mansion, who borrowed her name from the New York City mayor's official residence, had a charisma that made her and her gallery one of its favorite subjects. After three well-attended shows in her apartment, her landlord put a halt to her exhibitions and she moved her gallery to a larger space at 15 St. Mark's, then shortly after to 337 East Tenth Street between Avenues A and B. An integral part of the East Village art scene by the mid-80's, the Gracie Mansion Gallery, ran with the assistance of Sur Rodney Sur from 1983-1989, was one of the best known in the East Village during this boon.
Mansion specialized in large group exhibitions, theme shows that dramatically restyled the gallery, and the creative marketing of small affordable art. She represented a synthesis of painting and sculpture, art and environments, as opposed to single isolated objects. Among the artists she represented were Claudia DeMonte, Rodney Alan Greenblat, Ed McGowin, David Sandlin, Hope Sandrow, David Wojnarowicz, and Rhonda Zwillinger.
Eventually, Mansion relocated the gallery to SoHo and then Chelsea before closing in 2002 to focus on private dealing and the secondary market.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the New York City contemporary Gracie Mansion Gallery measure 5.3 linear feet and date from 1972-1991. Most of the records date from the gallery's opening in 1982 and later. The bulk of the collection consists of printed material and exhibition loan files that document the activities of the gallery and the East Village art scene. Loan and consignment files are found for numerous artists including Michael Bidlo, Buster Cleveland, Claudia DeMonte, Rodney Alan Greenblat, Stephen Lack, Ed McGowin, David Sandlin, Hope Sandrow, David Wojnarowicz, and Rhonda Zwillinger, among others. Also found are scattered business records.
Extensive printed material includes newspaper and magazine clippings, exhibition catalogs, and artists' files. Exhibition loan files are found for artists, exhibitions, and art fairs. These files contain consignment and loan agreement forms, correspondence, exhibition announcements, newspaper and magazine clippings, negatives and slides of artwork and exhibition installations, and a handful of color photographs of artwork or exhibition locales.
Scattered business records include correspondence, returned consignment forms from 1982-1987, donation records and materials related to art auctions, artist commissions, various lists, materials related to the Gracie Mansion Museum Store, notes, and a variety of other documents related to gallery operations.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 3 series:
Series 1: Printed Material, 1972-1991 (Boxes 1-2, 6; 0.80 linear feet)
Series 2: Exhibition Loans, 1982-1991 (Boxes 2-4; 2.25 linear feet)
Series 3: Business Records, 1982-1991 (Box 5; 1 linear foot)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Bidlo, Mike; Cleveland, Buster, d. 1998; DeMonte, Claudia, 1947-; Greenblat, Rodney Alan, 1960-; Lack, Stephen; McGowin, Ed, 1938-; Sandrow, Hope, 1951-; Wojnarowicz, David; Zwillinger, Rhonda
Subjects-Topical:
Art galleries, Commercial -- East Village (New York, N.Y.); Art, Modern -- 20th century -- New York (State) New York; Artists -- United States; Art dealers
Types of Materials:
Photographs
Names:
Mansion, Gracie
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Printed Material, 1972-1991, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-2, 6; 0.8 linear feet)
  This series contains primarily newspaper and magazine clippings concerning the East Village art scene, the gallery's exhibitions, and the artists it represented, such as Claudia DeMonte, Rodney Alan Greenblat, Ed McGowin, and David Sandlin; and the East Village Art Scene in the 1980s. Only two press clippings date from the 1970s and the rest from 1982-1991. Found also are artist resumes and a handful of exhibition catalogs from shows that the gallery lent artwork to, such as the 1985 International Contemporary Art Fair in London.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  1.1: General, 1982-1989
  1.2: Artist, 1972-1991
  - General, 1982-1989, Subseries 1.1:
    This subseries is arranged in chronological order.
    - 1982 April (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1982 June (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1982 July (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1982 September (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1982 November (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1982 December (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1983 January (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1983 March (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1983 April (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1983 May (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1983 June (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1983 July-August (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1983 September, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - 1983 October, (Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 1) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1983 November, (2 folders; Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 2) (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
    - circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1984 January (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1984 February (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1984 March, (Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 3) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1984 April, (Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 4) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1984 May, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
    - 1984 June, (Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 5) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 1984 July, (Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 6) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 1984 August (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 1984 Summer (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 1984 September (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - 1984 October, (Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 7) (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - 1984 November, (Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 8) (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - 1984 December (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - circa 1984, (2 folders; Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 9) (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
    - 1985 January, (2 folders; Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 10) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - 1985 February (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1985 March (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1985 April (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1985 May (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1985 June (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1985 July (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1985 August (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1985 Summer (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1985 September (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1985 October (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 1985 November (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 1985-1986 Fall/Winter (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - circa 1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 1986 Summer (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 1986 August-October (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1986-1987 Fall/Winter (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Artist, 1972-1991, Subseries 1.2:
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by artist.
    - Mac Adams, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Buster Cleveland, 1981-1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Claudia DeMonte, 1979-1990 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Rodney Alan Greenblat, 1983-1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Jean Lowe, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Kathleen McCarthy, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Ed McGowin, 1972-1990 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Gary Panter, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - David Sandlin, 1984-1991 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Louis Sciullo, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Fred Wilson, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - May Wilson, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Exhibition Loans, 1982-1991, Series 2:; (Boxes 2-4, 2.25 linear feet)
  This series contains documents relating to exhibition loans including consignment and loan agreement forms, correspondence,exhibition announcements, newspaper and magazine clippings, negatives and slides of artwork and exhibition installations, and a handful of color photographs of artwork or exhibition locales.
  The series is arranged as 3 subseries:
  2.1: Artist, 1983-1991
  2.2: Group, 1982-1989
  2.3: Organization, 1982-1991
  - Artist, 1983-1991, Subseries 2.1:
    - Mac Adams: Sable/Castelli Gallery, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Guy Augeri (Box 2)
      - Consignment Forms,1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - J. Barrett Gallery,1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Buster Cleveland (Box 2)
      - Consignment Forms,1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Kenneth Bernstein Gallery,1989 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - "Summer Pop Invitational," Sensory Evolution Gallery,1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Weatherspoon Art Gallery,1990 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Claudia DeMonte (Box 2)
      - Consignment Forms,1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - "Homage to Hopper," Baruch College Gallery,1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Brentwood Gallery,1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Decordova Museum,1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Evanston Art Center,1988 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Goddard-Riverside Community Center,1990 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Hudson River Museum,1988 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Islip Art Museum,1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Jamaica Art Center,1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Nabisco Brands Gallery,1989 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Maryland Faculty Show, National Academy of Sciences,1989 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - New Mexico State University1990 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Nina Freudenheim Gallery,1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - "Mermaids and Myths," San Francisco International Airport,1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - "American Art, American Woman," Stamford Museum and Nature Center,1985 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - Steven Scott Gallery,1988 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - University of Albany,1989 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - University of Maryland,1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - Maryland Faculty Show, University of Maryland, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - The Museum of Modern Art,1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      - "Commuting," Whitney Museum of American Art,1989 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Jonathan Ellis (Box 3)
      - "Figurative Sculpture," Everson Museum, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Hallwalls Contemporary Arts Center,1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Michael Kohn Gallery,circa 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Michael Ensminger: "Viral Infection: The Body and Its Discontents," Hallwalls Contemporary Arts Center, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Rodney Alan Greenblat (Box 3)
      - Consignment Forms, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Loan Agreements, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Greenville County Museum, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Haggerty Museum, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Hickory Museum, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - John Berggruen Gallery, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - "Mechanized Art," John Michael Kohler Arts Center, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Margulies Gallery, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Ron Bernstein, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - School of Visual Arts, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Whitney Museum of Art, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Al Hansen: Salvatore Ala Gallery, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Mike Howard (Box 3)
      - Consignment Forms, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Eliat Gordin Gallery, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - New Museum, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Union County College, New Jersey, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Weatherspoon Art Gallery, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Christof Kohlhofer/Marilyn Minter (Box 3)
      - Consignment Forms, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Boca Museum, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Galerie Charles Cartwright, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Stephen Lack (Box 3)
      - Consignment Forms, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Australian National Gallery, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Fay Gold Gallery, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Franklin Mint, Franklin Center, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Gallery Association of New York State, 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Graham Modern Gallery, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - G.W. Einstein Gallery, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Jan Baum Gallery, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - "The Arts of Drawing," Staempfli Gallery, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Ed McGowin (Box 3)
      - Consignment Forms, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Barbara Fendrick Gallery, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Center for the Arts, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Franz Bader Gallery, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Mississippi Museum, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - Sherry French Gallery, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Gary Panter (Box 3)
      - Future Perfect Gallery, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - Mambo Graphics,1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Ted Rosenthal: Salvatore Ala Gallery, 1984-1990 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Alison Saar: "Artists Against Racial Prejudice," The Clocktower Gallery, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - David Sandlin (Box 3)
      - Consignment Forms, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Art Awareness Inc., 1990 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Grace Borgenicht Gallery, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - "New York at Night," Helander Gallery, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - James Madison University, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - La Luz de Jesus Gallery, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - National Museum of American Art, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - "Art of the Madonna," Old St. Patrick's Church, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - State University of New York, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - "Space III," University of Alabama, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Hope Sandrow (Box 3)
      - Alternative Museum, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - "Bad Girls," Center for Contemporary Art, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - G.H. Dalsheimer Gallery, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 57)
      - "Photography on the Edge," Haggerty Museum, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 58)
      - Solo Show, Haggerty Museum, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 59)
      - Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, Smithsonian Institution, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 60)
      - "Large as Life: Contemporary Photography," Jamaica Arts Center, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 61)
      - Les Rencontres D'Arles International Photography Festival, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 62)
      - Marian Locks Gallery, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 63)
      - Museum of Modern Art, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 64)
      - "Photography of Invention," National Museum of American Art, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 65)
      - San Francisco Camerawork, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 66)
      - SUNY at Binghamton, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 67)
      - Tavelli Gallery, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - David West: Galerie Vivant, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - David Wojnarowicz (Box 3)
      - Consignment Forms, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 70)
      - Loan Agreements, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 71)
      - "Street Art," Boca Raton Museum, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 72)
      - Holly Solomon Gallery, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 73)
      - University Art Galleries, Illinois State University, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      - Laurence Miller Gallery, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      - Rosenberg Era Art Project, Long Island University, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 76)
      - Milford Gallery, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 77)
      - Norton Gallery of Art, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 78)
      - Phenix City Gallery, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 79)
      - University of Pennsylvania, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Rhonda Zwillinger (Box 3)
      - Consignment Forms, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 81)
      - Loan Agreements, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 82)
      - David Brown Gallery, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 83)
      - Exit Art, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 84)
      - "Century '87," Foundation of Independent Arthistorical Investigation, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 85)
      - Gallery 10 Ltd., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 86)
      - Rhonda's Japan Tour, Laforet Museum, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 87)
      - Newport Harbor Art Museum, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Group, 1982-1989, Subseries 2.2:
    - Art Fairs (Box 3)
      - ARCO, Spain, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 89)
      - Forum Art Fair, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 90)
      - International Art Fair Kunstrai, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 91)
      - International Gallery Invitational, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 92)
      - The Second International Contemporary Art Fair, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 93)
      - Zurich Art Fair, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Betsy Rosenfeld Gallery, Inc., 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Brent Gallery, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Brentwood Gallery, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Brooklyn Museum, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Colombia Show, Centro Colombo Americano, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Charles D. Irwin, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "Fresh," Dilaurenti Gallery Ltd., 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "A Brave New World, A New Generation," Exhibition Hall of Copenhagen, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Fashion Moda Organization, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Fondation Cartier, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Galerie Barbara Farber, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Galerie Specht, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Gallery Stolkholm Mobile, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Gloria Luria Gallery, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - "Gone Fishing," Graham Modern, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "Innocence and Experience," Greenville County Museum of Art, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Hartwick College, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Indianapolis Museum, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "New, Used, and Improved Art for the '80s," Karl Bornstein Gallery, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - La Collection Francaise, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Limbo Gallery, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Livet Reichard Co., 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Moosart Gallery, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Park Avenue Synagogue, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - AIDS Benefit, Sotheby's, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "Slaves of New York," The Gallery, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - "Arf Art," Trabia-MacAfee Gallery, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Wessell O'Connor Gallery, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, Fairfield County, 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Wilson Arts Center, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Organization, 1982-1991, Subseries 2.3:
    - "Art What Thou Eat," Blum Art Institute, Bard College, 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - "Sequence (Con)sequence," Blum Art Institute, Bard College, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - "Drive!" BMW Gallery, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - "Toys Art Us," Bronx Council on the Arts, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - "Reagan: American Icon," Bucknell University, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Columbus Museum, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Everson Museum of Art, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Gallery 91, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Galerie Eric Fabre Paris, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - "Psycho Pueblo," Galerie Fernando Vijande, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Galerie Marie-Louise Wirth, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - "Freedom of Painting," Galerie Paradis, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - "Images of Death in Contemporary Art," Haggerty Museum, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - "New Work, New York," Helander Gallery, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - "Serious Fun," Helander Gallery, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Hudson and Shiell Fine Art, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Hudson River Museum, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - "The Road Show: The Automobile in Contemporary Art," John Michael Kohler Arts Center, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Krasdale Foods Art Gallery, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - "Five London Women," La Mama Gallery, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Littlejohn-Smith Gallery, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - "Re: Framing Cartoons," Loughelton Gallery, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - "Romanticism and Cynicism," Marquette University, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - MIT List Visual Arts Center, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Women's Caucus for Art, Moore College of Art, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - "Contemporary American Beadwork," National Museum of American Art, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - New Gallery, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Park Avenue Synagogue, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Pyramid Arts Center, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Queens Museum, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - "Mythic Moderns," Real Art Ways Art Space, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - "Lost/Found," Rosemont College, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Sally Hawkins Gallery, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Salon des Artistes, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - "Products and Promotion," San Francisco Camerawork, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - San Francisco International Airport, 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Ted Gallery, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - "New York Now," The Gothenberg Art Gallery, 1986-1990 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - "AIDS: The Artists' Response," The Ohio State University, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - "Post Alabama Contemporary Artists," University of Alabama, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Wadsworth Atheneum Museum of Art, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Weatherspoon Art Gallery, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - "Art and the Law," West Publishing Company, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - "Suburban Homelife," Whitney Museum of American Art, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Business Records, 1982-1991, Series 3:; (Box 5, 1 linear foot)
  Scattered business records include correspondence; returned consignment forms from 1982-1987; donation records and materials related to art auctions; artist commissions; various lists, including a list of selected group shows and a list of artist lectures; materials related to the closure of the Gracie Mansion Museum Store, including final sales records; a folder of notes relating to possible shows; and a variety of other documents related to gallery operations.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Art Now Gallery Guide, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Artist (Box 5)
    - Claudia DeMonte: Meyers Commission, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)